I'm an industrial designer,
أنا مصمم صناعي،
which means I create all these cool things
ما يعني أنني أصنع كل تلك الأشياء الرائعة
from ideas that we surround ourselves with, or in this case,
من أفكار نحيط أنفسنا بها، أو في هذه الحالة،
geeky people surround themselves with, for the most part.
الأشخاص غريبو الأطوار يحيطون أنفسهم بها، في الغالب.
I have absolutely no background in biology, chemistry or engineering,
ليس لدي أي خلفية في الأحياء الكيمياء أو الهندسة بالتأكيد،
so bear with me, because I'll be talking about biomedical engineering today.
لذا تحملوا معي لأنني سأتحدث اليوم عن الهندسة الطبية الحيوية.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And please do stay here in the meantime.
ومن فضلكم أبقوا جالسين هنا في الوقت الراهن.
Industrial design is about making lots of things identical.
التصميم الصناعي هو عبارة عن جعل الكثير من الأشياء متطابقة.
The downside about that is, there's something impersonal
الجانب السلبي منه هو أن هناك شيء غير شخصي
about lots of identical things,
حول الكثير من الأشياء المتطابقة،
because when you're trying to design one thing for one person
لأنك عندما تحاول تصميم شيء واحد لشخص واحد
to solve one issue,
لحل مشكلة واحدة،
you can't really do that
لا تستطيع حقًا فعل ذلك،
when you're making things aimed more to a demographic model
عندما تفعل أشياء تستهدف نموذج سكاني
or to a marketing requirements document,
أو لوثيقة متطلبات التسويق،
which is what we live by.
وهو ما نعيش به.
So I got disheartened by the whole process in general,
لذا أصبت بخيبة أمل من العملية كاملة بشكل عام،
and went to rethink it and redesign designing altogether,
وعدت لإعادة النظر فيه وإعادة تصميم التصيم تمامًا،
went way back to my early, early design inspirations,
عدت للوراء لبدايتي، بداية إلهامات التصميم،
and back to about eight years old, and that got me to this guy.
عدت لقرابة الثمانية أعوام، وذلك أوصلني لهذا الشاب.
Anyone here from MIT knows him
أي شخص من معهد ماساتشوستس للتكنولوجيا يعرفه،
or has a tattoo or poster of him somewhere.
أو لديه وشم أو ملصق له في مكان ما.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Anyone else in the room, just for a hint,
أي شخص آخر في الغرفة، لمحة فقط،
he is the engineer of engineers or the designer of designers.
هو مهندس المهندسين أو مصمم المصممين.
He is the guy who made bionics a household word
هو الشخص الذي جعل البيولوجيا الالكترونية كلمة مألوفة.
in the form of the polyester-clad Six Million Dollar Man
في شكل البوليستر-كلاد رجل تساوي قيمته ستة مليون دولار،
that I grew up with.
ذلك الذي كبرت به.
The thing that came from this pop culture show,
الشيء الذي أتى من ثقافة عرض البوب،
the real takeaway, was two main things:
أن الأمر الحقيقي كان شيئين رئيسيين:
if you're designing for the person, for a real person,
إذا كنت تصمم لأجل الشخص، لشخص حقيقي،
you don't settle for the minimum functional requirements;
لا ترضى بأقل المتطلبات العملية؛
you see how far beyond that you can go,
أنت ترى البعد الذي يمكن أن تصل إليه،
where the rewards really are way out in the fringe
حيث المكافآت هي حقا وسيلة للخروج في الهامش
of how far past that document you can go.
في البعد الذي تستطيع الوصول إليه بعيدًا من الوثيقة.
And if you can nail that,
وإذا استطعت تثبيت ذلك،
you stand to improve the quality of life for somebody
أنت تقف لتطوير جودة الحياة لشخص ما
for every moment for the rest of their life.
لكل لحظة لبقية حياتهم.
I kind of distilled that down into a design philosophy,
أنا نوعا ما وضعته في فلسفة تصميم،
and infuse that into the studio that I have now;
وإدماج ذلك في الاستديو الذي لدي الآن؛
I'm trying to get everyone to think along these lines.
أحاول جعل الجميع يفكرون بهذه الأسطر.
It's not a profound philosophy, but it works for us.
إنها ليست فلسفة حديثة ولكن تعمل بالنسبة لنا.
We work with prosthetic limbs,
نحن نتعامل مع أطراف اصطناعية،
and the first thing you see about prosthetic limbs
وأول ما تراه حول الأطراف الصناعية
is that they are engineering brilliance.
هو أنها من إبداع المهندسين.
They can do amazing things;
هم يستطيعون فعل أشياء رائعة؛
they can return all kinds of functionality and performance
يستطيعون إعادة كل أنواع الوظائف والأداء
back to somebody's life.
لحياة شخص ما.
But from the vantage of an industrial designer,
ولكن من الأفضلية للمصمم الصناعي،
they're not quite there.
هم ليسوا هناك حقًا.
What we don't see is the sculpture or the beauty or the individual qualities
مالا نراه هو النحت أو الجمال أو الكفاءات الفردية
or the uniqueness or the elegance to them.
أو التفرد أو الأناقة لهم.
They are brilliant, mechanical, utilitarian devices.
هم مبدعون، ميكانيكيون، أجهزة ذات منفعة،
And that's great, except for a lot of people, that doesn't work.
وهذا عظيم، لكن للكثير من الناس، ذلك لا يعمل.
People come to our studio all the time,
يأتي الناس إلى الاستوديو لدينا طوال الوقت،
and they have bubble wrap and duct tape,
ولديهم لفات فقاعات وشريط لاصق،
trying to approximate their original form.
في محاولة لتقريب شكلها الأصلي.
Or they'll have a gym sock stuffed with other gym socks
أو لديهم جورب نادي محشي بجوارب نادي أخرى
to try to recreate the shape that once was;
لإعادة الشكل الذي كان سابقًا؛
and that, to us, is not thriving.
وهذا بالنسبة لنا غير مبهج.
The body, to us, is not a mechanical entity,
الجسد بالنسبة لنا ليس آلة،
where mechanical-only solutions can address them.
حيث حلول الميكانيكيين فقط يمكن أن تليق به.
It's our personal sculpture, our kinematic sculpture.
إنه نحت شخصياتنا نحت حركاتنا.
It is our canvas;
إنها لوحتنا؛
it represents not just our physicality,
لا يمثل هذا المنظر الجسدي فقط،
but also a lot of our personality as well.
ولكن الكثير من شخصياتنا أيضا.
So when you're designing for the body,
لذا عندما تصمم للجسد،
maybe the thing isn't to design for mass production,
ربما الأمر ليس أن تصمم لإنتاج ضخم،
but to design with the body in mind,
ولكن أن تصمم والجسد في عقلك،
to really think about curves instead of hard geometry,
أن تفكر حقا في المنحنيات بدلًا من علوم الهندسة المعقدة،
or uniqueness instead of identical.
والفرادة بدلًا من التطابق.
The problem is, we're constrained by mass production,
المشكلة هي أننا مقيدون بالإنتاج الضخم،
which makes a million identical things
والذي يصنع مليون شيء متطابق
but can't make one unique, individualized thing.
ولكن لا يستطيع صنع شيء واحد شخصي.
So we scrapped that in the new design process,
لذا ألغينا ذلك في طريق التصميم الجديد،
and we start with the person.
وبدأنا مع الشخص.
This is a three-dimensional scanner,
هذه ماسحة ثلاثية الأبعاد،
and that's what happens when you scan somebody:
وهذا مايحدث عندما تمسح شخصًا ما؛
you get three-dimensional data into your computer.
تحصل على بيانات ثلالثية الأبعاد في جهازك الكمبيوتر.
You can take the sound-side limb there, the surviving limb, mirror it over,
تستطيع أخذ شكل الطرف الآخر هناك، الطرف الناجي، وتنسخه،
and from now on,
ومن الآن فصاعدًا،
anything in the process will recreate symmetry --
أي شيء في العملية سينتج نسخة...
something as personal and as hard to achieve
شيء شخصي وصعب الإنجاز
as symmetry in the body.
كنظير في الجسد.
And you create a product that, no matter what,
وتصنع منتج مهما يكن،
it's going to be as unique as their fingerprint.
سيصبح فريد كبصمات أصابعهم.
In fact, our process is incapable of creating two identical things.
في الواقع مشروعنا غير قادر على صنع شيئين متطابقين.
So we run it through computer modeling, 3D CAD.
لذا نضعه في حاسوب نمذجة ثلاثية الأبعاد CAD.
Here, we actually infuse a lot of the individual's taste and personality
هنا، نحن ننتج الكثير من الأذواق الفردية والشخصيات
into it, everywhere we can,
في التصميم، في أي مكان نستطيع،
and we three-dimensionally print the results.
ونطبع النتيجة بطابعة ثلاثية الأبعاد.
We call the resulting parts "fairings,"
نسمي الأجزاء الناتجة" هدايا"،
because they're named after the panels on a motorcycle
لأنهم تم تسميتهم بعد لوحات الدراجات النارية
that turn it from a mechanical thing into a sculptural thing.
وذلك يحوله من شيء ميكانيكي إلى شيء حركي.
We tried this on Chad.
جربنا هذه الطريقة على تشاد.
Chad is a competitive soccer player,
تشاد لاعب كرة قدم منافس،
lost his leg eight years ago to cancer.
فقد قدمه قبل ثمانية سنوات بسبب السرطان.
You can imagine, it's really tricky to play soccer
يمكنك أن تتخيل إنه حقا من المحيل أن تلعب كرة القدم
when you have titanium pipe where there used to be a leg.
عندما تمتلك تيتانيوم في المكان الذي اعتادت أن تكون هناك ساق.
The resulting parts recreated his shape
لذا أجزاء النتائج أعادت صنع شكله،
and deliberately had an aesthetic that look like sporting gear.
وبشكل معتمد لديه حس يشبهه المعدات الرياضية.
We wanted it to make it look like he just pulled it out of the gym bag,
أردناه أن يصنعه بشكل كأنه سحبه من حقيبة النادي،
so it's fairly utilitarian in that regard.
لذا فهو نافع إلى حد ما في هذا الصدد.
Two things happened.
حدث أمران.
One, we expected: his sense of his body came back to him.
الأول أننا توقعنا: شعوره بجسده عاد إليه.
He was suddenly able to control the ball, to feel the ball,
أصبح فجأة قادرًا على التحكم بالكرة والشعور بها،
because his body remembered that original shape that he had had
لأن جسده تذكر الشكل الأصلي الذي كان يمتلكه
up until eight years ago.
حتى ثمان سنوات مضت.
The other thing, though, is that the other members of the team
الأمر الآخر هو: أن أعضاء الفريق الآخرين
stopped thinking of him as the amputee on the team.
توقفوا عن التفكير فيه كمبتور القدم في الفريق.
Not that they didn't know, but it stopped becoming a focal point for him.
ليس لأنهم لم يعلموا، ولكنها توقفت عن كونها نقطة الارتكاز فيه.
And there is a certain very quiet value in that,
وهناك قيمة مؤكدة في ذلك،
we like to believe.
أننا نحب أن نؤمن.
James lost his leg in a motorcycle crash.
فقد جيمس قدمه في حادث دراجة نارية.
And the motorcycle is still a big part of James's personality and style.
ولا تزال الدراجة النارية جزء كبير من شخصية جيمس وأسلوبه.
Check out the tattoo on his forearm.
تفقد الوشم في يده.
We three-dimensionally printed that into what would be his calf.
طبعنا ذلك بطابعة ثلاثية الأبعاد إلى ما سيصبح جلده.
He has his tattoo, he has his morphology
لديه وشمه، لديه الموروفولجي خاصته
and he has the materials of his motorcycle.
ولديه مواد دراجته النارية.
And the result is interesting in that you can't really tell at first glance
والنتيجة مثيرة فأنت لن تستطيع المعرفة من النظرة الأولى
where the motorcycle stops and where James starts.
حيث توقفت الدراجة النارية وبدأ جيمس.
It's kind of a chimera hybrid between the two,
إنه نوع من الكيميرا الهجين بين الاثنين،
and James likes that.
وجيمس أحب ذلك.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
So, we don't ever try to make something look like it could be human.
إذا، فنحن لا نحاول أبدًا صنع شيء يبدو وكأنه يمكن أن يكون إنسانا.
Our whole goal is to be unapologetically man-made,
هدفنا هو أن يكون صنع رجل،
to take what's already there, morphology,
لأخذ ما هو هناك بالفعل، علم التشكيل،
and just make it really cool and beautiful,
وجعله رائع وجميل حقًا،
something that somebody can't wait to show the world,
شيء لا يستطيع شخص أن ينتظر ليريه العالم،
because that changes their look.
لأن ذلك قد غير مظهرهم.
You don't look at him and say, "He's an amputee with a prosthetic."
لا تنظر إليه وتقول "إنه مبتور اليد بعضو صناعي."
You say, "He's a guy with something really cool going on.
تقول: "إنه رجل بشيء رهيب جدًا معه."
Deborah wanted her curves back,
ديبورا أرادت أن تعود تقوساتها،
but she also just wanted what came out of it to be really sexy,
ولكنها أيضا أرادت فقط ما أتت به من التقوسات وهو أنها مثيرة للغاية،
which is great for us to hear.
وهو رائع لنا أن نسمعه.
We created this lace pattern that lends itself well to 3D printing.
صنعنا نموذج رباط الحذاء الذي يقوّم نفسه للطباعة ال3D.
We created the first leg, I think,
صنعنا الساق الأولى، أعتقد،
where the lace defines the contour of the leg,
حيث يحدد الرباط محيط الساق،
instead of the leg giving form to the lace.
بدلًا من أن تعطي الساق الشكل للرباط.
We switched things over.
لقد حولنا الأمور.
What I like about this shot is you can see daylight through it.
ما أحبه في هذه اللقطة هو أنك تستطيع رؤية ضوء النهار خلالها.
So we're not trying to hide anything;
لذا فنحن لا نحاول إخفاء أي شيء؛
the load-bearing carbon component is totally visible.
حاملة عنصر الكربون مرئية تمامًا.
We're just giving it form and shape and contours
نحن فقط نعطيها تكوين وشكل وملامح
that were hers to begin with.
التي كانت لها لتبدأ بها.
We made her another leg that matched her purse,
صنعنا لها ساق أخرى تماشي محفظتها،
just because we could.
فقط لأننا استطعنا.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
We made another one where we laser-tattooed the leather,
صنعنا واحدة أخرى حيث وشمنا الجلد بالليزر،
because how cool would it be
لأنه كم هو رائع يمكن أن تكون
to be able to change your tattoos out from one minute to the next?
أن تستطيع تغيير وشمك من دقيقة لأخرى؟
Love that.
أحببت ذلك.
We try to capture as much of somebody's personality as we can.
نحن نحاول أن نلتقط الكثير عن شخصية الفرد بقدر ما نستطيع.
This is George. His will be finished next week.
هذا جورج. سيتم الانتهاء من ساقه الصناعية الأسبوع القادم.
This is the raw computer data that we deal with.
هذه بينات الحاسب الخام التي نتعامل معها.
He's kind of a classic, timeless-type personality,
هو نوعًا ما كلاسيكي، يفتقد للوقت ذلك النوع من الشخصيات،
so we did herringbone tweed, but in polished nickel.
لذا استخدمنا صوف خشن متعرج ولكن في نيكل مصقول.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And Uve was all too proud to show his tattoos,
ويوفي كان فخورًا جدا ليعرض وشومه،
so we are laser-tattooing those into the leather.
لذا وشمنا هذه في الجلد بالليزر.
Part of it is, yes, we're showing off, because we can do this,
جزء منه، نعم، نحن نتباهى لأننا نستطيع فعل ذلك،
but the other part is this connects him to what will be a part of him.
ولكن الجزء الآخر هو هذا الربط بينه بما سيكون جزء منه.
That is something really valuable; we believe in that.
هذا شيء قيّم حقًا؛ نحن نؤمن بذلك.
Tattoos are especially exciting for us.
الأوشام خصوصًا مثيرة لنا.
What happens if you take the tattoo,
ما يحدث إذا أخذت الوشم،
which is a combination of somebody's personal taste and choice,
وهو تضامن بين ذوق الفرد واختياره،
and their morphology,
وتشكيلهم،
but now, let's say, you remove the person.
ولكن الآن، لنقل أنك أزلت الشخص،
You get a free-floating tattoo defining their body.
تحصل على وشم حر يعبر عن أجسادهم.
So everything we do is about recreating and expressing something
إذا كل ما نقوم به يدور حول إعادة إنشاء والتعبير عن شيء ما
that means something to that person,
يعني شيء لذلك الشخص،
and expressing that through what would be their body,
والتعبير عن ذلك بما يمكن أن يكون جسدهم،
whether it's speed or attitude or bling,
سواء كان السرعة أو السلوك أو التفاخر،
whatever it is that captures and suggests them in the best way we can.
أي شيء يصور ويشير إليهم بأفضل طريقة ممكنة.
Back to the 3D-printing thing and this whole process:
لنعود للطباعة ثلاثية الأبعاد وكل هذه العملية:
we have a process that lends itself to making one thing per person;
لدينا عملية تضفي نفسها لصنع شيء واحد لكل شخص؛
it's very individual, and it actually really lends itself well to complexity.
إنه فريد للغاية، وهو في الواقع يفسح المجال للتعقيد.
So why not just print the entire leg?
إذا لما لا نطبع القدم كاملة فقط؟
That's the concept that preceded the work we're doing now.
هذا المفهوم الذي سبق العمل الذي نقوم به الآن.
This is a three-dimensionally printed leg. It's symmetric to the other leg.
هذه قدم مطبوعة 3D. إنها متماثلة مع القدم الأخرى.
It is made in America,
صنعت في أمريكا،
it is a trivially low-carbon footprint to create, curbside recyclable,
هي بصمة قدم مسلية منخفضة الكربون لصنع جانب طريق قابل لإعادة التدوير،
costs about 4,000 dollars to create,
تكلفة صنعها حوالي 4000 دولار،
and it is dishwasher-safe.
وهي آمنة ضد غسالة الصحون.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
There's a value to that, too.
هناك قيمة لذلك أيضا.
People don't think about that all the time,
الناس لا يفكرون في ذلك دائمًا،
but yes, throw it in the dishwasher, it works just great.
ولكن أجل، ضعه في غسالة الأطباق، وسيعمل بشكل رائع.
This was based on the original idea that I could go anywhere in the world
كان هذا ضمن الفكرة الأصلية التي تقول أستطيع الذهاب لأي مكان في العالم
with nothing more than a camera and a laptop computer,
بلا شيء أكثر من كاميرا وحاسب محمول،
use the camera as a 3D scanner and create for somebody, in a matter of hours,
استخدم الكاميرا كماسحة ضوئية 3D واصنع لشخص ما في غضون ساعات،
a very high-quality, three-dimensionally printed leg for a very low cost.
قدم مطبوعة 3D بجودة عالية وتكلفة منخفضة جدا.
The proof of concept works great, we're finding it; we'll get there.
الدليل للمفهوم يعمل بشكل رائع نحن نعثر عليه؛ نحن سنصل.
Or, we upped the quality of the materials and created this for John.
أو، رفعنا جودة المواد وصنعنا هذه لجون.
The fun thing with John's leg is that when his fiancee looked at this,
الأمر الظريف حول قدم جون هو أنه عندما نظرت خطيبته إليها،
she joked and said, "I like that leg better than that leg."
مزحت وقالت: "أعجبتني هذه القدم أكثر من تلك."
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And it's a joke -- she knows full well what he goes through --
وهي مزحة... هي تعرف جيدًا ما جرى له...
but at the same time, there's something very valuable.
ولكن في الوقت ذاته، هناك شيء قيّم للغاية.
He turned to us and said, "Nobody says that."
التف إلينا وقال: " لم يقل أحد ذلك."
He's never heard that in his life.
لم يسمع ذلك في حياته من قبل.
That connected with him very deeply.
ارتبط معه ذلك بشكل عميق جدًا.
So we like to think that this is a new type of design,
لذا نحب أن نفكر فيه على أنه نوع جديد من التصميم،
where you're turning the original process on its head,
حيث تحول العملية الأصلية في عقله،
where there is a dialogue that forms between the designer and the end user,
حيث هناك حوار يتشكل بين المصمم والمستخدم النهائي،
where the designer relinquishes some of the control --
حيث بتنازل المصمم عن بعض التحكم...
designers hate doing that --
يكره المصممون فعل ذلك...
and instead, is the curator of a process.
وبدلًا من ذلك، الوصي على المشروع.
And the end user relinquishes their body into the process, and their taste.
والمستخدم النهائي يتنازل عن جسده في العملية، وذوقه.
I'd like to think that speaks to a greater change that's happening
أحب أن أفكر أن ذلك يتحدث لتغيير كبير يحدث
in the design world altogether;
في عالم التصميم كله،
in this case, it's one where products will be evaluated
في هذه الحالة، إنها واحدة حيث يتم تقييم المنتجات
on how well they address the individual.
في كم هي جيدة لتصف الفرد.
The individual will actually be part of the DNA of the end product itself.
الفرد في الواقع سيكون جزء من DNA المنتج الأخير نفسه.
We will be evaluating products on how well they address a unique person,
سنطور منتجات في كم هم جيدون لوصف شخص متفرد،
instead of a demographic model.
بدلا من نموذج ديموغرافي.
This all really hit home for us in one of the first legs we did;
هذا كله يضرب الوتر لنا في واحدة من أوائل الأقدام التي صنعناها،
when Chad here put on the leg,
عندما وضع تشاد الساق هنا،
reached down and felt it
وصولا للأسفل وشعر بها
and thought about it for a while.
وفكر فيه لمدة.
Then he turned to us and said,
ثم التفت إلينا وقال:
"That's the first time I've felt that shape in eight years."
"هذه أول مرة أشعر بهذا الشكل من ثماني سنوات."
We thought about that.
فكرنا في هذا.
And for all the technology
وفي كل التقنية
and all the nights and energy we put into it,
وكل الليالي والطاقة التي وضعناها فيه،
that's all we really wanted to hear.
هذا كل ما أردنا حقًا أن نسمعه.
Thanks.
شكرًا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)